Richard Halliburton Papers, 1900-1973: Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Special Collections.
- Series 4: Photographs, 1918-1939; 24 boxes (2 partial)
  - Subseries 4A: Photographs Related to His Works, 1919-1939; 19 boxes (6 partial)
    - Seven League Boots, 1932-1935; 7 boxes (6 partial)
      - Christophe's Citadel, 1934; portions of 2 boxes
        - Christophe's Citadel, Photographs, 1934; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Christophe's Citadel, Negatives, 1934; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - Crusaders, 1932-1935; portions of 2 boxes
        - Crusaders, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Crusaders, Glass Plate Negative, circa 1932-1935; 1 5 x 7" glass plate negative 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Elephant Trip, Photographs, 1935; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Ethiopia, 1932-1935; portions of 2 boxes
        - Ethiopia, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Ethiopia, Negatives, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 15)
      - Fort Jefferson, 1932-1935; portions of 3 boxes
        - Fort Jefferson, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - Fort Jefferson, Negatives, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Fort Jefferson, Damaged Negatives, circa 1932-1935; Damaged acetate negatives 1 folder (Folder 5)
          Includes 2 damaged acetate negatives. Duplicates.
      - Gozo, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Hobson, Merrimac, Cuba, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Leningrad, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Middle East, 1932-1935; portions of 2 boxes
        - Middle East, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        - Middle East, Negatives, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Moscow, 1932; portions of 2 boxes
        - Moscow, Photographs, 1932; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Moscow, Negatives, 1932; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Mrs. Lenin and Russian Women, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Romanov Massacre, 1932-1935; portions of 2 boxes
        - Romanov Massacre, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Romanov Massacre, Negatives, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Russian Schools, 1932; portions of 2 boxes
        - Russian Schools, Photographs, 1932; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Russian Schools, Negatives, 1932; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - The Oldest Man in the World, 1932-1935; portions of 2 boxes
        - The Oldest Man in the World, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - The Oldest Man in the World, Negatives, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - Vladivostok, 1932-1935; portions of 2 boxes
        - Vladivostok, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Vladivostok, Negatives, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Watling's Island, Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - Miscellaneous, 1932-1935; portions of 2 boxes
        - Miscellaneous Photographs, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 6)
        - Miscellaneous, Negatives, circa 1932-1935; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Subseries 4B: Personal and Travel Photographs, 1918-1939; 11 boxes (7 partial)
    This subseries includes photographic materials related to Halliburton's personal life and other travels, including portraits of Halliburton, portraits of his Princeton University friends, and photographs of his Hangover House residence, his boat the Sea Dragon, and other subjects. Also present are his show slides (glass lantern slides) which document his travels and which he likely used in giving public talks about his adventures.
    - Richard Halliburton Portraits, Photographs, circa 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      6 photographs.
    - Richard Halliburton Portraits, Negatives, circa 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - Richard Halliburton Portrait, Damaged Negative, circa 1920s-1930s; Damaged acetate negative 1 folder (Folder 6)
      Includes one severely damaged acetate negative. Duplicate.
    - Richard Halliburton Portrait, Copper Photogravure Plate, circa 1920s-1930s; Copper photogravure plate mounted on wooden block 1 box
    - Friends at Princeton, Photographs, circa 1918-1921; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      9 photographs, 62 negatives.
    - Friends at Princeton, Negatives, circa 1918-1921; 1 folder (Folder 10)
    - Studio Portraits of Richard Halliburton and Friends at Princeton, Photographs, circa 1918-1921; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      6 8x10" individual studio portraits of Richard Halliburton and friends by Orren Jack Turner of Princeton, New Jersey.
    - Richard Halliburton with Helen Halsey, at Cape Porpoise, Maine, Photograph, 1919; AM 1993-132; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      1 photograph.
    - Hangover House, Laguna Beach, Photographs, circa 1937-1939; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      10 photographs. Interior and exterior shots of Richard Halliburton's home.
    - Sea Dragon, Photographs, 1939; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      18 photographs, 11 negatives.
    - Sea Dragon, Photograph by Robert Pullen, 1939; AM 2014-56; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      Oversize photographic print and and digital copy of Richard Halliburton's junk Sea Dragon before its fatal sail, taken by Robert Pullen. Copy of contemporary portrait of Pullen is included.
    - Sea Dragon, Negatives, 1939; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - "Nelle's Trip," Europe (Italy and Switzerland), Photographs, circa 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Princeton Pictorial Staff, Photographs, 1920-1921; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Honolulu, Photographs, circa 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Honolulu, Negatives, circa 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Boulder Dam Construction (Hoover Dam), Photographs, 1934-1936; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      Includes 19 black-and-white photographs, primarily of the dam under construction, and a tourist guide titled "View-Book of the Boulder Dam."
    - Golden Gate Bridge Construction, Photographs, circa 1933-1937; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Miscellaneous Travel, Photographs, circa 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Miscellaneous Travel, Negatives, circa 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous Photographs and Illustrations, circa 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 19)
    - Greece and Italy, Photographs, circa 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 20)
    - Seri People, Tiburón Island, Photographs, circa 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 21)
    - Seri People, Tiburón Island, Negatives, circa 1920s-1930s; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Travel Scrapbook, circa 1920s-1930s; 1 box
      Contains approximately 40 leaves of a scrapbook (unbound) with photographs partially pasted on each page (sometimes on both sides of the page) taken during Halliburton's worldwide travels. Also includes one mounted photo of Dahl Lake in Kashmir.
    - John the Baptist, Glass Plate Negatives, undated; 6 5 x 7" glass plate negatives 1 folder (Folder 9)
    - "The Man with the Golden Helmet" Print, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Show Slides, circa 1920s-1930s; 4 boxes
      Includes 141 numbered and 28 unnumbered glass lantern slides that are positive and in color. Numbered slides were removed from their original carrying case and sleeves were numbered to indicate their original order. Unnumbered slides were found loose. The numbered slides seem to be arranged in order of display and are apparently Halliburton's show slides. 4 broken slides (housed in Box 51) were encapsulated in archival plexiglass to facilitate handling.
    - Glass Plate and Film Negative Packaging, circa 1918-1939; 1 box
- Series 5: Papers of Others, 1903-1949 March 27; 8 boxes (2 partial)
  Arranged into three subseries by person.
  This series consists of papers of others collected by Richard Halliburton, including papers of Rupert Brooke and Wesley Halliburton, and papers regarding John Wilkes Booth and Richmond Pearson Hobson.
  - Subseries 5A: Rupert Brooke, 1904 May-1932; 5 boxes (1 partial)
    Arranged by genre of material.
    Consists of the papers of Rupert Brooke, including his works, correspondence, memorabilia, clippings, and photographs.
    - Works, 1904 May-1919; 2 boxes
      - The Bastille, A Prize Poem, 1905; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Cuttings About Rupert Brooke and Poems, 1907; 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - 1914 and Other Poems, 1915; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Poems, 1913; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - The Pyramids, 1904 May; 1 folder (Folder 5)
      - A Souvenir of Lenzerheide, 1909-1910; 1 folder (Folder 6)
      - An Unpublished Letter from America, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Unpublished Poems, undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
      - Copybooks 1-10, 1910s; 10 folders (Folder 1-10)
    - Correspondence, 1905-1916; 50 folders
      - Letters by Rupert Brooke, 1905-1915; 20 folders
        - Asquith, Lady Violet (Bonham-Carter), 1914-1915; 1 folder (Folder 1)
        - Cornford, Frances C. (Darwin), 1908-1914; 1 folder (Folder 2)
        - Cotterill, Erica, 1911; 1 folder (Folder 3)
        - Cox, Katherine, 1914; 1 folder (Folder 4)
        - Darwin, Gwen (Raverat), 1911-1914; 1 folder (Folder 5)
        - Drinkwater, John, 1912-1915; 1 folder (Folder 6)
        - Eckersley, Arthur, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
        - Garnett, David, 1911; 1 folder (Folder 8)
        - H., Geoffrey, 1906-1913; 1 folder (Folder 9)
        - Helena (NLN), 1914; 1 folder (Folder 10)
        - Hornby, Hon., undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
        - Loines, Russell, 1913; 1 folder (Folder 12)
        - Lucas, St. John, 1905-1907; 3 folders (Folder 13-15)
        - Murray, Rosalind (Mrs. Arnold Toynbee), 1912; 1 folder (Folder 16)
        - Nesbitt, Cathleen, 1913-1915; 1 folder (Folder 17)
        - Pye, Sybil, 1911-1915; 1 folder (Folder 18)
        - Raverat, Jacques, 1908-1915; 1 folder (Folder 19)
        - Rothstein, undated; 1 folder (Folder 20)
        - Wells, Chauncey, 1913; 1 folder (Folder 21)
        - Wells, Chauncey, Mrs., 1914; 1 folder (Folder 22)
      - Letters to Rupert Brooke, 1909-1915; 22 folders
        - Abercrombie, Lascelles, 1913; 1 folder (Folder 23)
        - Asquith, Lady Violet (Bonham-Carter), 1914-1915; 1 folder (Folder 24)
        - Barker, H. Granville, 1909-1913; 1 folder (Folder 25)
        - Beerbohm, Max, undated; 1 folder (Folder 26)
        - Benson, M., 1913; 1 folder (Folder 27)
        - Cannan, Gilbert, 1913; 1 folder (Folder 28)
        - Darwin, Frances C., undated; 1 folder (Folder 29)
        - Drinkwater, John, 1912-1915; 1 folder (Folder 30)
        - Ervine, St. John G., 1913; 1 folder (Folder 31)
        - Flecker, James Elroy, 1910; 1 folder (Folder 32)
        - Forster, F.M., 1910; 1 folder (Folder 33)
        - Gosse, Edmund, 1915; 1 folder (Folder 34)
        - Horniman, A.E.F., 1913; 1 folder (Folder 35)
        - Huffer, Ford Madox, 1909; 1 folder (Folder 36)
        - James, M.N., 1913; 1 folder (Folder 37)
        - Lytton, Neville, 1909; 1 folder (Folder 38)
        - Masefield, John, 1912-1915; 1 folder (Folder 39)
        - Monra, Harold, 1913; 1 folder (Folder 40)
        - Russell, Bertrand, undated; 1 folder (Folder 41)
        - Sidgewick, Frank, 1914; 1 folder (Folder 42)
        - Trevelyan, undated; 1 folder (Folder 43)
        - Yeats, W.B., 1913; 1 folder (Folder 44)
      - Letters of Others, 1914-1916; 8 folders
        - Asquith, O., to Violet Asquith Bonham-Carter, 1915; 1 folder (Folder 45)
        - Browne, W. Denis, to Mrs. Brooke, 1915; 1 folder (Folder 46)
        - Browne, Denis, to Parents, 1914-1915; 1 folder (Folder 47)
        - Masefield, John, to Violet Asquith Bonham-Carter, 1915; 1 folder (Folder 48)
        - Quitter, Arnold C., to E. Marsh, 1915; 1 folder (Folder 49)
        - Shaw-Stewart, Patrick, to E. Marsh, 1915; 1 folder (Folder 50)
        - Wells, Chauncey, to E. Marsh, 1916; 1 folder (Folder 51)
        - Miscellaneous Letters, undated; 1 folder (Folder 52)
    - Rupert Brooke as Subject, 1913-1932; 7 folders
      - Introduction to Halliburton's Collection on Rupert Brooke, undated; 1 folder (Folder 1)
      - Rupert Brooke - Colophon, 1932. by Augustus Bridle, 1 folder (Folder 2)
      - Rupert's Grave, to Mrs. Brooke from Private in RMLI, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
      - Poems about Rupert Brooke, 1913; 1 folder (Folder 4)
      - Cuttings on Rupert Brooke, 1915; 2 folders (Folder 5-6)
      - Rupert Brooke's Death and Burial, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
      - Memorials for Rupert Brooke, undated; 1 folder (Folder 8)
    - Memorabilia, 1915-1932; 7 folders
      - Memorial for Raymond ‘Oc’ Asquith, undated; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      - Memorial for Victor Barrington Kennett, undated; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      - Memorial for William Charles Denis Browne, undated; 1 folder (Folder 11)
      - Memorial for Bernard Cyril Freyberg, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
      - Memorial for Frederick Septimus ‘Cleg’ Kelly, 1927; 1 folder (Folder 13)
      - Memorial for Patrick Shaw-Stewart, undated; 1 folder (Folder 14)
      - Memorabilia, 1915-1932; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1929; 2 folders
      - Robinson Jeffers, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
      - Rupert Brooke, 1929; 1 folder (Folder 17)
    - Rupert Brooke, Photographs, undated; 1 folder (Folder 18)
    - Rupert Brooke, Glass Plate Negatives, undated; 5 3.25 x 4.25" glass plate negatives 1 box
  - Subseries 5B: John Wilkes Booth, Richmond Pearson Hobson, 1934-1938; portions of 2 boxes
    Arranged alphabetically by subject.
    Consists of articles about John Wilkes Booth and photographs of landmarks related to Booth (grave, hiding place, etc.). Also includes papers regarding Richmond Pearson Hobson.
    - John Wilkes Booth Clippings, 1938; 1 folder (Folder 1)
    - John Wilkes Booth, Photographs, undated; 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - John Wilkes Booth, Negatives, undated; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Lord Byron, Photographs, undated; 1 folder (Folder 3)
    - Lord Byron, Negatives, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Hobson, Now and Then, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Richmond Pearson Hobson, Congressional Record, 1934; 1 folder (Folder 5)
    - R.P. Hobson, House of Representatives, 1934; 1 folder (Folder 6)
    - Appointment of R.P. Hobson: Senate, undated; 1 folder (Folder 7)
    - Hearing on House of Representatives 9221, Appointment of R.P. Hobson, 1934; 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Subseries 5C: Wesley Halliburton, 1903-1949 March 27; 2 boxes (1 partial)
    Consists of the papers of Wesley Halliburton, including "Death Valley Scotty's Fabulous Life Story and Magnificent Castle Enchant Memphian" and a document for "Certificate Award as Master of the Royal Secret of the 32nd Degree of the Ancient and Accepted Scottish Rite."
    - Death Valley Scotty's Fabulous Life Story and Magnificent Castle Enchant Memphian, 1949 March 27; 1 folder (Folder 9)
      Newspaper clipping.
    - Letter and Photographs Regarding Richard Halliburton's Disappearance at Sea, 1938-1939; 1 folder (Folder 10)
      Includes a TLS from Wesley Halliburton to Rev. and Mrs. George J. Lapp, Dec. 8, 1939, regarding his son Richard, the building of his Junk boat in Hong Kong, Dec. 1938, photographs, and newspaper clippings about his disappearance at sea, 1939.
    - Printed Letter to Columnist, 1945 April 20; 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - Letter from US Navy to W. Halliburton, undated; 1 folder (Folder 12)
    - Halliburton and Moore Southern Farms and Timberlands Ledger, undated; 1 folder (Folder 13)
    - Certificate Award as Master of the Royal Secret of the 32nd Degree of the Ancient and Accepted Scottish Rite, 1903; 1 folder (Folder 14)
    - Blueprint: Plot from Records by Memphis Abstract Co., 1944 May; 1 folder (Folder 15)
    - Wesley Halliburton, Photographs, undated; 1 folder (Folder 16)
    - Scrapbook, undated; 1 box
- 32101037102868 (Box 1)
- 32101037102876 (Box 2)
- 32101037102884 (Box 3)
- 32101037102892 (Box 4)
- 32101037102900 (Box 5)
- 32101037102918 (Box 6)
- 32101037102926 (Box 7)
- 32101037102934 (Box 8)
- 32101037102942 (Box 9)
- 32101037102959 (Box 10)
- 32101037102967 (Box 11)
- 32101037102975 (Box 12)
- 32101037102983 (Box 13)
- 32101037102991 (Box 14)
- 32101037103007 (Box 15)
- 32101037103015 (Box 16)
- 32101037103023 (Box 17)
- 32101037103031 (Box 18)
- 32101037103049 (Box 19)
- 32101037103064 (Box 20)
- 32101037103072 (Box 21)
- 32101037103080 (Box 22)
- 32101037103098 (Box 23)
- 32101037103106 (Box 24)
- 32101037103114 (Box 25)
- 32101037103122 (Box 26)
- 32101080526682 (Box 27)
- 32101080526690 (Box 28)
- 32101080526708 (Box 29)
- 32101080526716 (Box 30)
- 32101080526724 (Box 31)
- 32101080526732 (Box 32)
- 32101080526740 (Box 33)
- 32101080526757 (Box 34)
- 32101080523614 (Box 35)
- 32101080523622 (Box 36)
- 32101080523630 (Box 37)
- 32101080523648 (Box 38)
- 32101080528811 (Box 39)
- 32101037103262 (Box 40)
- 32101037103270 (Box 41)
- 32101037103288 (Box 42)
- 32101037103296 (Box 43)
- 32101037103304 (Box 44)
- 32101080523655 (Box 45)
- 32101080528886 (Box 46)
- 32101080528894 (Box 47)
- 32101080528902 (Box 48)
- 32101080528910 (Box 49)
- 32101080528928 (Box 50)
- 32101080526666 (Box P-000017)
- 32101080526674 (Box P-000018)
- 32101080528829 (Box P-000047)
- 32101080528837 (Box P-000048)
- 32101080528845 (Box P-000049)
- 32101080528852 (Box P-000050)
- 32101080528860 (Box L-000008)
- 32101080528878 (Box L-000009)
- 32101080529322 (Box 51)
- 32101080529330 (Box 52)
- 32101086132774 (Box B-000880)